<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Hi, I am David</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Hi, I am David</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>true</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to customize shiny sliderInput</title>
      <link>/blog/customsliderinput/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/customsliderinput/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you might get bored by the design of the sliders in Shiny. This input widget uses the Ion.Rangeslider js library. In the advanced section, you can notice that 5 themes are actually available. I really like the flat ui skin. In this tutorial, I will describe one way to install new themes for your shiny sliders.
 First of all, you have to download shiny from source in order to access some files required for this customization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Shiny packages</title>
      <link>/blog/bestofshiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bestofshiny/</guid>
      <description>After several months of silence (I am very busy :)), I would like to share with you a &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; of all Shiny packages you might need to build beautiful and powerful applications.
Enhance your apps with Javascript (still updated) The shinyjs package was designed by Dean Attali, https://deanattali.com/shinyjs/, a very famous shiny user. In summary, it allows you to add interactivity inside your app for example:
 hide/show/toggle widgets, graphs, tables reset inputs to their initial value enable/disable elements  These are the most outstanding properties of this package and require just a few lines of code to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Updates</title>
      <link>/blog/todolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/todolist/</guid>
      <description>Future updates:
add a link to the second scientific article published upload the first shiny app in the Lorenz model section add all other shiny apps related to the Lorenz model open the shiny showcase section new icons update the Lotka Volterra App publish Shiny App of Calcium Homeostasis add a description part to the Calcium Homeostasis gallery add tutorials/articles in the teaching section  Last update: 22-10-17</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting MathJax with Hugo</title>
      <link>/blog/mathjax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mathjax/</guid>
      <description>The classical approach MathJax is a javascript library which allows the user to integrate math expressions in a website or a blog. However, its configuration can be quite complex for beginners. In my previous website powered by Jekyll, I easily managed to install MathJax, whereas I encountered some problems with Hugo.
1. Installing MathJax via Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation Everything you need can be found here. You have to insert the code below in the /layout/partials folder of your website: it is even better to create a file named mathjax_support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/blog/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hello/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my new website. I am David, PhD in mathematical physiology, especially in renal physiology and calcium/phosphate metabolism. I have a great interest for new technologies especially those dedicated to improve the learning process, as well as scientific collaboration. I often noticed that some scientific topics are really complex, thereby classical courses may not be sufficient to integrate all this complexity. During the past 5 years, I built several mathematical models from developmental biology (somitogenesis) to calcium and phosphate homeostasis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>